<xml>
<names>
<!--The first name listed here is the one that will show on your individual page-->
<name>Wesly S. Ménard </name>
		<!--Additional names are just to be extra-sure that any way your name would show up on a pub, it gets linked to you-->
		<name>Wesly Ménard </name>
		<name>Wesly Menard </name>
		
</names>
<sort_name>Ménard</sort_name>
<!--Here are the recognized positions you can choose from:
   Ph.D. Student
	Ph.D. Candidate
	Undergraduate Researcher
	Postdoctoral Research Associate
-->
<position>Ph.D. Student</position>
<program>Human-Centered Computing</program>
<school>University of Florida</school>
<email>w.menard@ufl.edu</email>
<bio>
Wesly Ménard is a Ph.D. student advised by Dr. Kristy Boyer in the Department of Computer &amp; Information Science &amp; Engineering at the University of Florida.

His research interests encompass AI integration of sensor technologies and wearables, athlete performance prediction, physiological optimization, collaborative and intelligent training platforms with real-time feedback, and biohacking. His current work seeks to utilize historical data, biometric information, and environmental factors to provide insights into optimal training strategies, nutrition, pacing, and injury prevention for athletes of all level. 

Wesly is exploring how data-driven technologies can promote social connection, motivation, and community among athletes through shared physiological data such as heart rate, while balancing privacy and customization needs. He is also leading an interdisciplinary project to develop a system enhancing awareness and safety for micro-motorists and drivers.

Outside of academia, Wesly is an avid cyclist, runner, Team USA age-group duathlete, and overall lover of anything outdoors. In his spare time, he enjoys writing, sketching, and painting.
</bio>

<degrees>
<degree>
<abbrev>Ph.D.</abbrev>
<subject>Human-Centered Computing</subject>
<graduation>Expected 2027</graduation>
<school>University of Florida</school>
</degree>
<degree>
<abbrev>M.Ed.</abbrev>
<subject>Educational Leadership</subject>
<graduation>2021</graduation>
<school>University of Tampa</school>
</degree>
<degree>
<abbrev>M.A</abbrev>
<subject>Secondary Science Education</subject>
<graduation>2017</graduation>
<school>University of South Florida</school>
</degree>
<degree>
<abbrev>B.S.</abbrev>
<subject>Biology &amp; Chemistry</subject>
<graduation>2010</graduation>
<school>Clayton State University</school>
</degree>
</degrees>
</xml>
