<xml>
	<name>INVITE Institute - Inclusive Intelligent Technologies for Education</name>
	<sort_id>1</sort_id>
	<tagline>INVITE seeks to fundamentally reframe how AI-based educational technologies interact with learners. We develop AI techniques to track and promote skills that underlie successful learning and contribute to academic success: persistence, academic resilience, and collaboration.</tagline>
	<description>
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Project Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;This NSF AI Research Institute is inventing, investigating, and deploying novel AI-augmented learning technologies and foundational AI techniques to address the needs of learners who are underserved and underrepresented in STEM. INVITE brings together a highly interdisciplinary and internationally-recognized team of researchers with expertise in AI, the learning sciences, psychology, and broadening participation with a network of diverse schools, districts and community partners to pursue these critical challenges. INVITE’s long-term research vision is to lay a foundation for a new generation of AI-augmented learning that supports learners in holistic ways.&lt;p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Project Description&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;INVITE’s research is pursuing foundational AI advances in robust and fair machine learning, cognitive architectures, and natural language understanding and use-inspired research focusing classroom integration of a suite of INVITE STEM learning platforms. Research will revolve around three interconnected strands: (1) Collect, analyze, and share novel datasets for AI to enable foundational AI advances in fair and robust machine learning and natural language understanding. Driving principles will emphasize representativeness, consistency, and shareability; (2) Build novel, robust methods for understanding learner behaviors and persistent, integrated learner models that incorporate novel assessments of noncognitive skills. (3) Develop new inclusive, socially-aware STEM learning environments that provide natural and adaptive interaction with socially aware pedagogical agents. 	&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more at the &lt;a href=”https://invite.illinois.edu/”&gt;INVITE Institute website.&lt;/p&gt;		
	</description>
</xml>
