<xml>
	<name>Pedal Florida</name>
	<sort_id>1</sort_id>
	<tagline>An Initiative to Increase Physical Activity in Cancer Survivors</tagline>
	<description>
		<!--
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Project Introduction&lt;/h4&gt; -->
	&lt;p&gt;Pedal Florida is an initiative to increase Floridians’ physical activity through outdoor social cycling. In the LearnDialogue lab we are investigating ways in which novel and AI-powered technologies can support both novice and experienced cyclists in achieving their physical activity goals. The research results will inform the design of technologies that support cyclists in planning and conducting social rides. 

Within this initiative, we have undertaken a Florida Department of Health funded research study to benefit Florida’s citizens, who include more than 200,000 cancer survivors. Even after fighting their battle with cancer, these survivors continue to face increased risk of morbidity and mortality. Extensive research shows the benefits of physical activity in combatting these risks, yet many cancer survivors lead sedentary lives. We aim to increase physical activity and social connectedness with an innovative citizen-led mentoring approach focused on cycling and facilitated by leading-edge technology. By partnering with cancer survivors in citizen-led cycling clubs already in existence throughout the state, the intervention is intended to be self-sustaining at a low cost after it is well established. &lt;p&gt;

		&lt;br&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Learn more at the &lt;a href=https://pedalfl.org&gt; Pedal Florida website. &lt;/a&gt;

		<!--
	&lt;p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Project Description&lt;/h4&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;We are establishing a train-the-trainer style intervention to recruit and train new outdoor cyclists. By partnering with cancer survivors in citizen-led cycling clubs already in existence throughout the state, this intervention is intended to be self-sustaining at a low cost after it is well established. Long-term, the project aims to significantly improve cancer survivorship through increasing physical activity, reducing isolation, and doing both of those in restorative outdoor spaces. &lt;p&gt;-->
	</description>
</xml>
